Guide to the Records of the Office of the President (Dr. James McNaughton Hester) RG.3.0.7
New York University Archives
- Series XIII: Interviews, Speeches, and Testimony, 1962-1975 (Boxes 80-87, 92)
  - Annual Masons and Sons Breakfast, "Regarding the Future", 1969 March 16 (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - Manhattan Cable Television Interview by Percy E. Sutton, 1969 April-May (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - The University Club, "The University and the Public: Crisis in Confidence", 1969 April 22 (Box 82, Folder 19)
  - Newsmakers Guest Appearance, WCBS-TV, 1969 April 27 (Box 82, Folder 20)
  - Statement on Student Dissent, 1969 April 30 (Box 82, Folder 21)
  - New York Chamber of Commerce Annual Membership Meeting, 1969 May 15 (Box 82, Folder 22)
  - Dorothy Gordon Youth Forum, "The University and the Community", 1969 May 4-11 (Box 82, Folder 23)
  - New York Chamber of Commerce, "The Challenge to Higher Education Today", 1969 May 11 (Box 82, Folder 24)
  - Speech to Guidance Counselors (Boston, MA), 1969 May 13 (Box 82, Folder 25)
  - Crozer Theological Seminary, "What Do We Ask of the Ministry?", 1969 June 3 (Box 82, Folder 26)
  - Trinity School Commencement, 1969 June 6 (Box 82, Folder 27)
  - New York University Commencement, "Our National Morale: What We Must Do About It", 1969 June 11 (Box 82, Folder 28)
  - Neuman Award Ceremony, Reconstructed Remarks (Israel), 1969 July 22 (Box 82, Folder 29)
  - General Electric College Bowl Commercial Voice-Over, 1969 August 19 (Box 82, Folder 30)
  - New York University Convocation for New Students, 1969 Fall (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Senate Finance Committee, Statement on Tax Reform Bill (HR 13270), 1969 September 25 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Rye Country Day, 1969 October (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Service for Dr. Sam Wortis of New York University Medical Center, 1969 October 8 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Institute of International Education Annual Dinner, 1969 October 9 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Hadassah Annual Convention (New Orleans, LA), 1969 October 14 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - African Scholarship Program of American Universities, 1969 October 30 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - "Pressures on the Urban University Today", 1969 October 31 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Reports to Alumni (Los Angeles and San Francisco, CA), 1969 November 14, 16 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - College and University Journal, "Reason is Answer to Gap" [Age Gap], 1969 Winter (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Campus in the City Conference, "One Approach to Higher Education", 1969 December 2 (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - New York University School of Education Commencement (Puerto Rico), 1969 December 6 (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - "The New Concept of 'Community'", 1970 (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - American Management Association Interview, 1970 January 29 (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - American Association of Dental Schools Annual Session, "Student Participation in the Education Process", 1970 January 6 (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Council of Churches Annual Dinner, "The Condition of the Christian Layman", 1970 January 22 (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - University of Lagos Annual Lecture, "The Competing Claims of Liberal and Professional Education in the Modern University" (Lagos, Nigeria), 1970 February 20 (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - American Management Association Study Interview (Excerpts), 1970 February 25 (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Kenan Inaugural Lecture, "Introduction of Professor Frank E. Manuel", 1970 March 12 (Box 83, Folder 19)
  - Syracuse University Honors Convocation, "Redefining the Educated Man", 1970 March 19 (Box 83, Folder 20)
  - American Association of Dental Schools Annual Session, "Student Participation in Academic Governance", 1970 March 22 (Box 83, Folder 21)
  - The President's Report, 1970 March 23 (Box 83, Folder 22)
  - Arnold Schwartz Dinner, 1970 April 16 (Box 83, Folder 23)
  - Statement to the Select Sub-Committee on Education, of the Education and Labor Committee, on HR 15933, 1970 April 24 (Box 83, Folder 24)
  - Texaco Round Table, 1970 April 30 (Box 83, Folder 25)
  - University Heights Philosophy of Education Class Lecture, 1970 April 30 (Box 83, Folder 26)
  - Magazine Publishers Association, "The Academic Revolution", 1970 May 19 (Box 83, Folder 27)
  - ABC's Issues and Answers Appearance (ABC Television), 1970 May 31 (Box 83, Folder 28)
  - Spence School Commencement, 1970 June 4 (Box 83, Folder 29)
  - International Association of Universities, "International University Cooperation in University Administration and Organization" (Montreal, Canada), 1970 August 31 (Box 83, Folder 30)
  - Urban Affairs Quarterly, "Some Observations on the Urban Involvement of Universities", 1970 September (Box 83, Folder 31)
  - National Association of College Admissions Counselors, "The University President and Student Unrest", 1970 October 1 (Box 83, Folder 32)
  - Radio WOR-AM Interview with Martha Deane, on Campus Violence (1 of 2), 1970 October 1-1971 January (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Radio WOR-AM Interview with Martha Deane, on Campus Violence (1 of 2), 1970 October 1-1971 January (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Harbison Award Ceremony: "E. Harris Harbison and Good Teaching", 1970 October 18 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - "Problems of Student Unrest at New York University", 1970 October 20 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - New York University Presidential Message, 1970 October 22 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Policy Association Off-the-Record Series, "College Students and Foreign Policy", 1970 November 4 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Packer Collegiate Institute 125th Anniversary, "Youth, The City, and Education", 1970 November 7 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - New York University Freshman Convocation, 1971 September (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - Newcomen Society, Speech on History of New York University, 1970 November 12 (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Newcomen Society, Speech on History of New York University (Correspondence About), 1970 January-February (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Newcomen Society, Speech on History of New York University (Correspondence About), 1970 March-June (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - Newcomen Society, Speech on History of New York University (Correspondence About), 1970 October-December (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Newcomen Society, Speech on History of New York University (Correspondence About), 1971 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Newcomen Society, Speech on History of New York University (Research Notes), undated, 1957-1968 (Box 84, Folder 11)
  - Newcomen Society, Speech on History of New York University (Research Notes), 1970 July-October (Box 84, Folder 12)
  - American Petroleum Institute, "The University President and Student Unrest", 1970 November 18 (Box 84, Folder 13)
  - University Heights Center, "Dedication of the Sculpture by Guitou Knoop", 1970 November 20 (Box 84, Folder 14)
  - New York University Dean's Day, 1970 November 21 (Box 84, Folder 15)
  - New York University Education Quarterly, "Changes in Governance at New York University" (Interview with Professor Henry J. Perkinson), 1970 Winter (Box 84, Folder 16)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1970 December 3 (Box 84, Folder 17)
  - "A Clear Strong Policy", 1970 December 15 (Box 84, Folder 18)
  - Presbyterian Life Interview, "College Students in America", 1971 January 15 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Real Estate Institute Urban Leadership Award Dinner, "The Campus Now", 1971 January 19 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - New York University School of Medicine Dean's Day, 1971 February 15 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Regents Conference, "Higher Education: The Critical Issues, the Leadership Role of the Trustee", 1971 February 18 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Testimony before House Sub-Committee on Appropriations for Labor, Health, Education, and Welfare, 1971 March 10 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - University Heights Presbyterian Church Sermon, 1971 March 14 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - U.S. House of Representatives Special Subcommittee on Education and Labor, "Statement of Higher Education Associations", 1971 March 30 (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Fordham University Commencement, 1971 June 5 (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Fordham University Commencement, "Private and Public Higher Education" (Reprinted in Thought), 1971 June 5 (Box 85, Folder 15)
  - New York University Commencement, 1971 June 7 (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - University of Pittsburgh Dedication, "The Durable Need and Perpetual Challenge for Academic Libraries", 1971 June 13 (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Rotary Club of New York, "Crisis in Higher Education in New York City", 1971 June 17 (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Institute of International Education Meeting (Nara, Japan), 1971 July 3 (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - New York University Parents' Convocation, 1971 September (Box 85, Folder 17)
  - Testimony Before the Board of Regents on Behalf of the Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York, 1971 September 9 (Box 85, Folder 18)
  - Testimony before Joint Legislative Committee on Higher Education, 1971 September 23 (Box 85, Folder 19)
  - Inauguration of Dr. Harold B. Whiteman at Sweet Briar College, 1971 October 13 (Box 85, Folder 20)
  - Central Presbyterian Church 150th Anniversary, "The Church, the University and the City", 1971 October 17 (Box 85, Folder 21)
  - Speech at Georgetown University (Includes Correspondence and Reference Materials), 1971 October 23 (Box 85, Folder 22)
  - New York Public Library Annual Dinner, 1971 November 16 (Box 85, Folder 23)
  - Testimonial Dinner for Herbert Silverman, B'nai B'rith, 1971 November 29 (Box 85, Folder 24)
  - Interview on "The Martha Deane Show", 1971 December 22 (Box 85, Folder 25)
  - "NYU Faces Critical Issues" (Reprinted in the New York Times), 1972 January 10 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Interview with New York Daily News, "Troubled Giant: NYU is Losing the Money Battle", 1972 February 11 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Conference on the Future of Higher Education in New York State, Skidmore College, "The Road to Rennslaerville", 1972 February 14 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Courant Memorial, 1972 February 18 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Century Club, "Ten Years as a University President", 1972 March 2 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Lotos Club State Dinner, 1972 March 22 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Bowery Savings Bank Board of Trustees Meeting, 1972 May 10 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Interview with New York Report, 1972 May 14 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - New York University Commencement, 1972 May 31 (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Statement to Newsweek, 1972 June 9 (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Annual Judicial Conference (Lake Placid, NY), 1972 June 23-24 (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - New York University Faculty Meeting, 1972 September (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Testimony at New York State Education Department Hearing on Baruch College, 1972 September 8 (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - Testimony before the Board of Regents (Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York), 1972 September 12 (Box 86, Folder 14)
  - "The Present State of New York University", 1972 September 18 (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - "Crises in Education--What Really Goes On", 1972 November 1 (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - Gallatin Dinner, 1972 November 30 (Box 86, Folder 17)
  - Urban Leadership Award Dinner, 1973 February 8 (Box 86, Folder 18)
  - Statement for College Management, 1973 March 21 (Box 86, Folder 19)
  - Newsweek Anniversary, "Problems and Prospects of Higher Education in the '70s" (Orlando, FL), 1973 April 17 (Box 86, Folder 20)
  - Statement, "What is the Future of New York City?", 1973 April 23 (Box 86, Folder 21)
  - Ettinghausen Reception, 1973 May 9 (Box 86, Folder 22)
  - Introduction to American Higher Education for Chinese Journalists, 1973 May 22 (Box 86, Folder 23)
  - New York University Commencement, "Universities and Morality", 1973 June 5 (Box 86, Folder 24)
  - New York University Parents' Convocation, 1973 September (Box 86, Folder 25)
  - Speech for Entering Students, "A New Era and a New Realism", 1973 September 18 (Box 86, Folder 26)
  - Radio Interview with WABC New York, [1973 September 23] (Box 86, Folder 27)
  - Foreign Policy Association Off-the-Record Luncheon, "Students and Foreign Policy", 1973 October 10 (Box 86, Folder 28)
  - Middle Atlantic Association of Colleges of Business Administration Meeting, "Ethics in Business Education", 1973 October 11 (Box 86, Folder 29)
  - Lotos Club, Tribute to Brooke Astor, 1973 November 15 (Box 86, Folder 30)
  - Day Care Council of New York Annual Meeting, "The University and Day Care", 1973 November 28 (Box 86, Folder 31)
  - Testimony before Board of Regents on Baruch College, 1973 December 13 (Box 86, Folder 32)
  - Profile in Organizational Dynamics, "Man at the Top", [1974] (Box 86, Folder 33)
  - "Grace Church School", 1974 January 27 (Box 86, Folder 34)
  - Real Estate Institute Dinner, Fourth Annual, 1974 March 13 (Box 86, Folder 35)
  - Editorial, Change, 1974 April (Box 86, Folder 36)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges Council of Deans, "New Problems in University Management", 1974 April 25 (Box 86, Folder 37)
  - Phi Chi Theta, College of Business and Public Administration, "Ethics in Business Education", 1974 April 30 (Box 86, Folder 38)
  - Council on Education for Public Responsibility, 1974 May 6 (Box 86, Folder 39)
  - B'nai B'rith Award Dinner, 1974 May 1 (Box 86, Folder 40)
  - New York University Commencement, "The Personal Impact of Watergate", 1974 June 6 (Box 86, Folder 41)
  - Staff Dinner (Notes), 1974 June 14 (Box 86, Folder 42)
  - Statement to U.S. House Subcommittee on Education, of the Committee on Education and Labor, 1974 August 12 (Box 86, Folder 43)
  - Wake Forest University Opening Convocation, "Personal Honor", 1974 August 29 (Box 86, Folder 44)
  - Wake Forest University Opening Convocation, "The Personal Impact of Watergate", 1974 August 29 (Box 86, Folder 45)
  - New York University Freshman Convocation, 1974 [September] (Box 86, Folder 46)
  - College of Business and Public Administration, "Social Responsibility fo Organizations in a Free Society", 1974 October 3 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Catholic Center Tenth Anniversary, "Religion and the Purposes of the University", 1974 October 17 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Brookdale Hospital Medical Center Presidential Tribute Ball, 1974 November 9 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Association of College and University Business Officers, "New Problems in University Management", 1974 December 8 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Afro-American Affairs Conference at New York University, 1975 February 7 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - American College Health Association, "New Problems in University Management", 1975 April 1-4 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - University of Pittsburgh Commencement, 1975 April 27 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - New York University Commencement, 1975 June 5 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Statement about the Alumni Fund for Alumni News (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Shockley Forum Speech Notes, undated (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Speeches, symposia, conferences, 1965-1966 (Box 92)
- Series XIV: Unprocessed Records (Box 90, Box 91)
  - Mission of New York University, 1962-1964 (Box 101, Box 102, Box 103)
  - unprocessed materials (Box 106)
  - Nellie Burmaster Files From Presidential Office, 1960s-1970s (Box 107)
    Custodial History
    Materials Transferred on 1/16/2020 from RG 3-0-10 (Office of the President--John Brademas) While processing the Brademas Presidential papers, the Archivist found this carton and determined they belonged in this collection. The files appear to be accumulated by the secretary/assistant to the NYU President in the 1970s.
- Records of Special Committees, Commissions, and Task Forces
  - Records of President Nixon's Task Force on Higher Education (Box 93, Box 94, Box 95, Box 96, Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100)
  - Goals Conference Papers, unprocessed (Box 104, Box 105)